Finding Aid for Lavender Information and Library Association records, 1989-2007
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Lavender Information and Library Association records 1989-2007
Lavender Information and Library Association, 1989-2007
2.0 linear feet
9916 Bimu 2
Organization established in 1989 by University of Michigan librarians and information science professionals and students to promote awareness of lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender issues within the university libraries and School of Information. Prior names have been Gay and Lesbian Library Staff (GALLS), Gay and Lesbian Library Association (GALLA), and Bisexual, Gay and Lesbian Library Association (BGALLA).
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Transferred from the Lavender Information and Library Association (donor no. 8255 ) in periodic accessions between 1994 and 1998. Additional material was donated by Scott Dennis in 2008 and 2013.
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The Lavender Information and Library Association record group is open for research except for the material in box 2. This material contains information deemed sensitive by the organization and is restricted for 50 years from the date of creation at the request of the organization.
The Lavender Information and Library Association (LILA) was formed in June 1989, by members of the University of Michigan library staff. The original name of the organization, Gay and Lesbian Library Staff (GALLS) reflected its founding membership. When the group decided to include library students as members, the organization's name was changed to the Gay and Lesbian Library Association (GALLA), which was later revised to Bisexual, Gay and Lesbian Library Association (BGALLA). In 1996, the name was changed to LILA to include transgendered people and to reflect changes in the library and information profession.
In 2013, LILA became Information Across the Spectrum, and was chiefly associated with the University of Michigan School of Infomation.
The mission of LILA was to promote awareness of lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender issues within the School of Information, the university libraries and throughout the university. It also served as a social and advocacy organization for gay, lesbian, bisexual, and transgendered library/information students and staff. LILA activities have included maintenance of a computer message board, promotion of social events, and building exhibits promoting awareness of its constituent communities. The organization also served as a liaison, working with the School of Information administration and student groups and maintaining relations with lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgendered organizations at the university.
The records of the Lavender Information and Library Association (LILA) are organized in five series: Electronic Mail, Meeting Minutes and Agendas, Publicity and Public Relations, Later Accessions, and Artifacts. Documentation details the events and activities of LILA as well as issues and events of general interest to the gay, lesbian, bisexual and transgender community.
Subjects:
Lavender Information and Library Association.; Gay college students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Gays--Michigan.; Homosexuality--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Lesbians--Michigan.; Sexual orientation--Michigan.; Libraries--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan--Students--Societies, etc.; University of Michigan. Library--Employees--Societies, etc.
- Electronic Mail (Print Outs)
  The Electronic Mail series is the largest group of records. It consists of print outs of incoming and outgoing electronic mail, which includes informal messages, agendas, minutes, and forwarded newsletters.
  - 1993-1995 (Box 1)
  - 1994, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1994-1995 (Box 1)
  - 1996, 5 folders (Box 1)
  - 1997, 7 folders (Box 1)
  - 1998 (Box 1)
- Meeting Minutes and Agendas
  The Meeting Minutes and Agendas series consists of agendas and minutes pertaining to LILA meetings.
  - BGALLA Agendas, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
  - BGALLA/GALLA Minutes, 1993-1994, 2 folders (Box 1)
- Publicity and Public Relations
  The Publicity and Public Relations series consists of flyers, brochures, public correspondence and press releases.
  - Pamphlets, flyers and public correspondence, 1989-1998 (Box 1)
  - Press Releases, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Photographs and captions of "Diversity and Thought in Deed" exhibit, ca. 1992 (Box 1)
- Later Accessions
  The Later Accessions series contains materials donated at various times by LILA member Scott Dennis.
  - Papers
    - 1989-1997 (Box 1)
    - 1998-2002 (Box 1)
    - 2003-2007 (Box 1)
  - Photographs
    - Photograph album of 10th anniversary party, 2000 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous photos (including CD) (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)
- Artifacts
  The Artifacts series consists of one BGALLA T-shirt and one LILA T-shirt.
  - T-shirts, 1992-1997 (Box 1)
- Restricted Files
  - Restricted Files, 1993-1998 (Box 2)
    (Restricted 50 years from date of creation)